-Hold. -What?
- Halte. - Quoi ?
Explain your sneeze.
Explique ton éternuement.
-l'm sorry? -Do you have allergies?
- Pardon ? - Allergies ?
-No. -Too much pepper on your salad?
- Non. - Salade trop poivrée ?
-I don't put pepper on salads. -l've heard enough. Sit over there.
- Je poivre jamais. - D'accord. Mets-toi là-bas.
Come on, I don't wanna sit by myself.
Je veux pas être tout seul.
That's what Typhoid Mary said. Clearly, her friends buckled.
Typhoid Mary a dit pareil. Ses amis ont cédé.
Guys, help me.
Aidez—moi.
-Sheldon, come on. -Yeah, it's just one sneeze.
- Sheldon. - Un simple éternuement.
-You're on your own. -See you, buddy.
- T'es tout seul. - A plus, mon pote.
Oh, Leonard, l have something for you.
Leonard, c‘est pour toi.
Per our roommate agreement, this is your 24-hour notice...
Le préavis, 24 heures avant,
...that I will be having a non-related female...
indiquant la venue d‘une femme non—parente
...spending two nights in our apartment.
chez nous, pour deux nuits.
When you say non-related female, you still mean human, right?
"Non—parente", mais tout de même de l'espèce humaine ?
Well, of course.
Bien sûr.
Pets are banned by the agreement, with the exception of service animals...
Nos accords excluent les animaux,
...such as Seeing Eye dogs and, one day...
sauf les chiens d'aveugle, et un jour,
...cybernetically enhanced helper monkeys.
les singes cyborgs domestiques.
Are you planning on kidnapping a woman?
Tu vas kidnapper une femme ?
-Sarcasm? -Yes.
- Du sarcasme ? - Oui.
But mixed with genuine concern.
Et une pointe d‘inquiétude.
For your information...
Pour ta gouverne,
...l'll be playing host to Dr. Elizabeth Plimpton.
je reçois le Dr. Elizabeth Plimpton.
-Cosmological physicist from Princeton? -Yes.
- La physicienne de Princeton ? - Oui.
And until you acquire a surgical mask...
Tant que tu n'as pas de masque chirurgical,
...please address your comments to me through a napkin.
merci de t'adresser à moi à travers une serviette.
We've been corresponding for years about our mutual interest...
On correspond depuis des années à propos
...in gravitational wave signatures of inflatons in the early universe.
des vagues d‘inflatons au début de l'univers.
Now she's under consideration for a position at our university.
Elle candidate dans notre université.
Why didn't you tell me you knew Elizabeth Plimpton?
Tu aurais dû me dire que tu la connaissais.
lam a huge fan of hers.
Je suis un grand admirateur.
I didn't realize I had to share my connection...
J'ignorais que je devais annoncer tout lien
...with things you're a fan of, but, very well.
avec les choses que tu apprécies.
You enjoy Canadian bacon. I've been to Toronto.
Tu aimes le bacon canadien : je suis allé à Toronto.
-Okay, fine. Where is she gonna sleep? -My room, of course.
- Où va-t-elle dormir ? - Dans ma chambre.
-Yeah, I have a two-part question. -Go ahead.
- Question en deux parties. - Vas-y.
A, are you kidding me?
A : tu plaisantes ?
And B, seriously, are you freaking kidding me?
Et B : sérieux, tu te fous de nous ?
A, I rarely kid.
A : je plaisante rarement.
And B, when I do kid, you will know it by my use of the word "buzzinga."
B : quand c‘est le cas, j‘utilise le mot ”buzzinga."
So you're saying the two of you are going to be sleeping in the same bed?
Vous allez dormir dans le même lit ?
Yes.
Oui.
Leonard?
Leonard ?
Thank you.
Merci.
Why is a renowned scientist staying in our apartment instead of a hotel?
Pourquoi une scientifique renommée n‘irait pas à l‘hôtel ?
She doesn't care for hotels. And who can blame her?
Elle n'aime pas ça, et on la comprends.
Windows that don't open, multi-user linens...
Fenêtres qui n‘ouvrent pas, linge réutilisé,
...keys shaped like credit cards.
clés en forme de cartes.
As if one walks around with unassigned slots in one's wallet.
Comme si on avait des espaces vides dans Ie porte-carte.
All right, I believe I have time for one more question.
J'ai le temps de prendre une dernière question.
Yes, Raj?
Oui, Raj ?
RAJESH: When can I sit with you again?
Je peux revenir quand ?
When I've seen two negative throat cultures spaced 12 hours apart.
Quand j‘aurai vu deux cultures négatives espacées de 12 heures.
You know the drill.
Tu connais.
All right, if you'll excuse me...
Excusez-moi,
...I am off to start a prophylactic course of antibiotics.
je vais commencer un traitement antibiotique préventif.
I can't believe he's friends with Elizabeth Plimpton.
J'en reviens pas, il est ami avec Elizabeth Plimpton.
I can't believe they let him into Canada.
J'en reviens pas, il a pu entrer au Canada.
Whoa. You heard the man. Where's your throat cultures?
Où sont tes cultures ?
-Kidding. Sit down. LEONARD: Ha.
Je blague, assieds-toi.
-Hey, Sheldon. -Oh, Penny, excellent.
- Salut. - Penny, excellent.
l have a question about these maxi pads.
J'ai une question sur ces serviettes.
Are the wings truly functional or have | fallen victim to marketing hype?
Les ailettes sont—elles utiles, où me suis-je fait avoir par le marketing ?
What? What are you doing with--? What?
Quoi ? Pourquoi ? Quoi ?
The stock boy at Walgreens was frustratingly uninformed on the subject.
Le vendeur était très mal informé à ce sujet.
Sheldon, what are you doing with maxi pads?
Que fais-tu avec des serviettes ?
SHELDON: l have a lady friend who will be staying with me for a few days.
Je reçois une amie pendant quelques jours.
What?
Quoi ?
SHELDON: I want her to feel at home.
Je veux qu'elle soit à l‘aise.
I also bought scented soaps, pantyhose, Midol, calcium chews...
J'ai du savon parfumé, des collants, des gommes au calcium,
...and what is apparently a yogurt specifically designed...
et un yaourt conçu spécifiquement
...to regulate the female bowel.
pour réguler le transit féminin.
Wait. Wait, hold on. Back up.
Attends. Pas si Vite.
You're having a woman stay with you?
Tu reçois une femme ?
Yes. Why does that seem to flabbergast everybody?
Oui. Pourquoi êtes-vous tous si estomaqués ?
PENNY: No, no, no, I'm not flabbergasted.
Je ne suis pas estomaquée.
I'm puzzled.
Je suis perplexe.
Yeah, let's go with puzzled.
On va dire ça, perplexe.
SHELDON: A word of warning:
Je t‘avertis :
My guest is a noted physicist...
mon amie est physicienne,
...and the leading expert on quantum cosmology...
experte incontestée en cosmologie quantique.
...so please try to avoid wasting her time with female gibber-gabber.
Ne lui fais pas perdre son temps avec des babillages de femme.
Female gibber-gabber?
Des babillages ?
Shoe sales, hair styles, mud masks...
Chaussures, coiffures, masques de boue,
...gossip about your friends, Brad and Angelina.
et les potins sur tes amis, Brad et Angelina.
PENNY: No, they're not my friends.
Ce ne sont pas mes amis.
SHELDON: Not surprised, considering how you talk about them behind their backs.
Pas étonnant, vu comment tu les critiques dans leur dos.
She's here. She's here. How do I look? Do I look smart?
Elle est la. Je suis bien ? J'ai l‘air intelligent ?
Oh, good grief. This isn't about you.
Mon Dieu, il ne s'agit pas de toi.
Coming.
J‘arrive.
Now, listen, one of the great minds of the 21st century...
Un des génies du 21ème siècle
...is about to play host to one of the other great minds of the 21st century.
va recevoir un des autres génies du 21ème siècle.
So pay attention.
Alors sois attentif.
Years from now, my biographer might ask you about this event.
Mon biographe te demandera des détails, dans quelques années.
Well, I have so many things to tell your biographer.
J‘aurai tant de choses à dire à ton biographe.
Oh, Dr. Cooper, thank goodness.
Dr. Cooper, dieu merci.
I completely forgot your address.
J‘avais oublié votre adresse.
But then, I remembered that I'd written it on my hand.
Je l‘avais notée dans ma main.
Lucky I didn't confuse it with what I'd written on my other hand...
Je n'ai pas confondu avec ce que j'ai dans l‘autre main :
...which are the coordinates for a neutron star.
les coordonnées d‘une étoile à neutrons.
Because if I tried to go there, I'd be crushed by hypergravity.
Si j‘avais essayé d‘y aller, la surpesanteur m'aurait tuée.
-Anyway, hello. -Hello.
- Bref, bonjour. - Bonjour.
-Nice to finally meet you in person. -I would imagine it is.
- Ravie de vous rencontrer enfin. - Je m'en doute.
This is my friend and roommate, Dr. Leonard Hofstadter.
Mon ami et colocataire, le Dr. Leonard Hofstadter.
Hi-Io.
Salour.
Oops. I started to say hi, and then I switched to hello in the middle.
Je voulais dire salut etj'ai bifurqué sur bonjour.
It came out "hi-lo."
Ce qui donne salour.
It's nice to meet you.
Enchanté.
I've read both your books and your papers.
J'ai lu vos livres et vos articles.
I'm Leonard. I live here. You're brilliant.
Je suis Leonard. Je vis ici. Vous êtes géniale.
I apologize. He's only an experimental physicist.
Pardon, c‘est un physicien expérimental.
No need to apologize. Some of my best friends are experimental physicists.
Ce n‘est rien, certains de mes meilleurs amis en sont aussi.
Well, not my best friends. But I know them.
Enfin, j'en connais, quoi.
My best friend is a molecular chemist named Wendy.
Ma meilleure amie, Wendy, est chimiste moléculaire.
I'm sorry, I'm rambling.
Pardon, je dis n‘importe quoi.
-Hi-Io. SHELDON: Heh, heh.
Salour.
Hungry? Can I offer you anything?
Je peux vous offrir quelque chose ?
If anyone should offer her anything, it should be me.
Si quelqu'un offre, ce sera moi.
Elizabeth, can I get you something?
Vous voulez quelque chose ?
Perhaps a feminine-hygiene product or a bowel-regulating yogurt?
Un produit d‘hygiène féminine ? Un yaourt régulateur du transit ?
Interesting choices.
Choix intéressant.
Based on my current needs, I guess I'd pick the yogurt.
Selon mes besoins actuels, j'opte pour le yaourt.
Excellent.
Excellent.
If the yogurt works, I bought some delightful scented candles.
S'il marche, j'ai aussi de délicieuses bougies parfumées.
Look, it's you.
C‘est vous.
Thank you so much for opening up your home to me.
Merci de me recevoir chez vous.
Well, who wants to stay in a hotel?
Qui voudrait aller à l‘hôtel ?
Windows that don't open, those crazy card-shaped keys.
Fenêtres qui ne s‘ouvrent pas, clés en forme de cartes.
I'm so glad you understand.
Quel bonheur que vous compreniez.
No, he doesn't understand.
Non, il ne comprend pas.
-I understand. -I understand too.
- Je comprends. - Moi aussi.
You're just misappropriating my understanding.
Tu usurpes ma compréhension.
I think any university would want you.
Toute fac voudrait de vous.
Except any university that already had you...
Sauf celle qui vous a déjà,
...because they would've already wanted you...
même si elle vous a déjà voulue,
...before they, you know, got you.
avant de vous avoir.
From the mind that brought you hi-lo.
Parle créateur de salour.
Let me show you to your room.
Je vous montre votre chambre.
All right, I guess I am tired.
Je suis un peu fatiguée.
-Good night, Leonard. -Sleep night.
- Bonne nuit, Leonard. - Dormez nuit.
I mean, obviously, good night.
Je veux dire : bonne nuit.
I started to say sleep tight. Then I changed my mind in the middle.
Je voulais dire dormez bien etj'ai changé d‘avis.
I swear to God, I'm smart.
Je vous jure que je suis intelligent.
Get it together, man.
Reprends-toi.
All right, let me show you some of the features of the room.
Je vous présente les équipements dela chambre.
First, windows. Conventional.
Des fenêtres. Conventionnel.
Open, closed. Open, closed.
Ouvert, fermé. Ouvert, fermé.
Halfway open, or halfway closed...
Mi-ouvert, mi-fermé.
...depending on your philosophical bent.
Tout est question de point de vue.
Over here is my comic-book collection. Feel free to browse.
Ma collection de comic-books, que vous pouvez parcourir.
There's a box of disposable reading gloves on the nightstand.
Il y a des gants de lecture jetables sur le chevet.
Good to know.
Bon à savoir.
In here, you'll find emergency provisions.
Ici, des provisions d'urgence.
An eight-day supply of food and water, a crossbow...
Des vivres et de l‘eau pour 8 jours. Une arbalète,
...season two of Star Trek: The Original Series...
la saison 2 de Star Trek: The Original Series
...on a high-density flash drive.
sur disque flash.
What if there's a disaster that destroys all the USB ports?
Et si un désastre détruisait tous les ports USB ?
Then there's really no reason to live, is there?
Alors à quoi bon vouloir survivre ?
Can I ask you a question about your roommate?
J'ai une question sur votre colocataire.
He's an odd duck, isn't he?
Il est étrange, non ?
What's his relationship status?
Est-il célibataire ?
Well, there was a misbegotten adventure...
Il y a bien eu une aventure malheureuse
...with a waitress who lives across the hall.
avec la serveuse qui habite en face.
It ended as inexplicably as it began.
Un mystère du début à la fin.
They had very little in common except for carnal activity.
Ils avaient peu en commun hormi l'activité charnelle.
That's why I acquired these noise-canceling headphones.
D'où l‘acquisition de ce casque antibruit.
If you decide to use them, please clean the earpieces afterwards...
Si vous l‘utilisez, merci de nettoyer les embouts
...with the Wet Wipes you'll find in the bathroom.
avec les lingettes dela salle de bain.
They're in the drawer labeled "Wet Wipes."
Elles sont dans le tiroir "lingettes".
-Okay. -Good.
- Ok. - Bien.
I'll leave you to your nighttime ablutions.
Je vous laisse à vos ablutions vespérales.
I've e-mailed you the morning bathroom schedule.
Je vous ai mailé le planning salle de bain.
You'll also find a laminated copy in your welcome packet.
Il y a une copie plastifiée dans votre pack de bienvenue.
On the back of the emergency-escape-route diagram.
Au dos du plan d‘évacuation.
How thoughtful.
Vous pensez à tout.
-Sleep well, my friend. -You too.
- Dormez bien, mon amie. - Vous aussi.
Let me just get one thing.
Je prends juste une chose.
It's my backup emergency supply kit.
Mon kit de secours de secours.
The living-room escape route doesn't pass through here.
La route d'évacuation du salon ne passe pas par ici.
Now, good night.
Bonne nuit.
And if there's an apocalypse, good luck.
Et en cas d‘apocalypse, bonne chance.
Yes?
Oui ?
-I saw your light on. -ls everything all right?
- J'ai vu votre lumière. - Tout va bien ?
Yeah, I just couldn't sleep.
J'arrive pas à dormir.
Me neither.
Moi non plus.
Look what I'm reading.
Regardez ce que je lis.
It's you.
C‘est vous.
-I thought you already read it. -I did.
- Vous l'avez déjà lu. - Oui.
But it's been a while, and I wanted to sound smart over breakfast.
Mais ça fait longtemps. Je veux avoir l‘air intelligent au petit-déj.
Aw, you're smart.
Vous êtes intelligent.
Oh, good. I wasn't sure it was coming across.
Bien, j'ignorais si ça se ressentait.
What chapter are you on?
Vous êtes à quel chapitre ?
Uh, six.
Six.
Ah. The extragalactic distance ladder.
L‘échelle de distance extragalactique.
-Want to know a little secret? -Sure.
- Vous voulez savoir un secret ? - Oui.
I wrote the section on the Wilson-Bappu Effect completely naked.
J'ai écrit la partie sur l‘effet Wilson-Bappu nue.
Really?
Vraiment ?
Sure doesn't read that way.
On le sent pas en le lisant.
Here, let me show you.
Je vous montre.
When we consider the brightness of pulsating variable stars...
Considérons la brillance des étoiles à pulsation variable.
...we start to see a possible explanation...
On entrevoit une explication possible
...for some of the discrepancies found in Hubble's constant.
à certaines failles dela constante de Hubble.
You really make science come alive.
Vous donnez vie àla science.
Vocal test.
Test vocal.
Morning vocal test.
Test vocal matinal.
Second vocal test. Second morning vocal test.
Second test vocal.
-Morning, Sheldon. -Morning.
- Bonjour, Sheldon. - Bonjour.
-I trust you had a pleasant night? -More than pleasant.
- La nuit a été bonne ? - Mieux que bonne.
Excuse me. I'm going to relieve myself.
Pardon, je vais me soulager.
-How do you take your coffee? -Black.
- Tu veux un café ? - Noir.
Okeydoke.
D‘accord.
SHELDON: Pee for Houston. Pee for Austin.
Pipi pour Houston. Pipi for Austin.
Pee for the state my heart got lost in.
Pipi pour l'état où j'ai perdu mon cœur.
And shake twice for Texas.
Et on se secoue deux fois pour le Texas.
Something his mother taught him.
Sa mère lui a appris ça.
All right. Elizabeth, the bathroom is yours.
Elizabeth, la salle de bain est à vous.
The seat is down and has been sanitized for your protection.
Le siège est baissé et a été désinfecté pour votre protection.
That's very thoughtful, but I think I'll finish my coffee first.
C‘est très gentil, mais je vais d‘abord finir mon café.
Ah, so the yogurt didn't work.
La yaourt a échoué, alors.
I'll fire off a critical e-mail to the manufacturer.
J'envoie un e-mail assassin au fabricant.
Oh, good, you're up. My car won't start.
Ma voiture ne démarre pas.
I need a ride to work.
Il faut me déposer au boulot.
Did you ignore your check-engine light?
Tu as ignoré l'alarme batterie ?
I ignored the fill-gas-tank light.
J'ai ignoré l'alarme réservoir Vide.
Leonard, Penny wants to exploit any feelings you have for her...
Penny veut exploiter tout sentiment à son égard
...in order to get a ride to work.
pour que tu la déposes au travail.
Oh, uh, sure, let me just put this in atravel mug.
Ok, je prends une tasse de voyage.
-Hello? -Hi.
- Bonjour ? - Salut.
Oh, Penny, this is Dr. Plimpton, a leading expert on quantum cosmology.
Le Dr. Plimpton, experte absolue en cosmologie quantique.
Dr. Plimpton, Penny is a waitress who doesn't understand...
Penny, une serveuse qui ne comprends pas
...the role gasoline plays in the internal combustion engine.
le rôle du gasoil dans un moteur à combustion.
-Nice to meet you. -Nice to meet you too.
- Ravie. - Moi aussi.
-Are you enjoying your stay? -Yes, very much.
- Vous vous plaisez ici ? - Enormément.
Wonderful. Meaningless pleasantries accomplished.
Merveilleux. Les platitudes ont été échangées.
Elizabeth, Leonard's bathroom time is coming up...
L‘heure de passage de Leonard àla salle de bain arrive,
...and, believe me, you do not want to follow him.
et mieux vaut ne pas l‘y succéder.
Excuse me.
Excusez-moi.
Okay, well, I guess I should get dressed so I can take everyone to work.
Je vais m'habiller pour emmener tout le monde au boulot.
You and Sheldon and Sheldon's friend, Dr. Plimpton, who you just met.
Toi et Sheldon, et l'amie de Sheldon, le Dr. Plimpton.
It'll be fun.
Ça va être drôle.
Like a clown car. Heh, heh.
Une voiture de clown.
-Hang on. -Hm, yeah? What? Huh?
- Attends. - Oui, quoi ?
We just broke up.
On Vient de rompre.
You and me? Yeah, we did.
Toi et moi ? Oui.
Not too long ago. How are you doing with it?
Il y a peu. Tu le vis comment ?
Not as good as you, apparently.
Moins bien que toi, apparemment.
I don't follow.
Je ne te suis pas.
You know, it's none of my business.
Ça me regarde pas.
You wanna sleep with Sheldon's buddy right after we broke up, go for it.
Tu peux t‘envoyer l'amie de Sheldon juste après notre rupture.
-Well, now-- SHELDON: Excuse me.
- Je... - Excusez-moi.
I'm uncomfortable with you recommending...
Je suis gêné que tu recommandes
...Leonard pursue intercourse with Dr. Plimpton.
à Leonard de copuler avec le Dr. Plimpton.
Who, I assure you, has better things to do.
Elle a bien mieux à faire.
I'm not recommending it.
Je ne le recommande pas.
I'm saying it already happened.
C‘est déjà fait.
Oh, that's preposterous.
C‘est absurde.
Tell her, Leonard.
Dis-lui, Leonard.
Well....
Eh bien...
Oh, come on. It wasn't my fault.
C‘est pas ma faute.
The implication being that you somehow tripped and fell into her lady parts?
Tu as trébuché et tu es retombé dans ses parties intimes ?
I'm just gonna take the bus to work.
J'irai bosser en bus.
-Penny, I can still drive you. -No, no, it's okay.
- Je peux te déposer. - Non, ça ira.
You might slip on a banana peel and get me pregnant.
Tu pourrais glisser sur une peau de banane et me mettre enceinte.
I must say, I'm shocked by this betrayal.
Je suis choqué par cette trahison.
I didn't betray Penny.
Je n'ai pas trahi Penny.
How am I betraying you?
En quoi je te trahis ?
Elizabeth's my friend, and you're playing with her.
Elizabeth est mon amie et tu jours avec elle.
Yeah, I guess I did.
J‘imagine que c‘est vrai.
What the hell are you doing?
Tu fais quoi ?
Relax, it's Nyquil.
Relax, c‘est du Nyquil.
-You still have a cold? -Maybe, but I don't care.
- Toujours enrhumé ? - Possible, mais je m'en fiche.
That's the great thing about Nyquil, it's like 10 percent booze.
C‘est grâce au Nyquil, et à ses 10% d‘alcool.
I call it the nighttime sniffling, sneezing, coughing...
Le médicament antitussif
...so-you-can-talk-to-girls medicine.
qui fait parler aux filles.
Are you having trouble sleeping?
Tu as du mal à dormir ?
Because, boy, I was up all night.
J'ai passé la nuit debout.
Did you get a cold too?
Tu es enrhumé ?
No, l was awake all night.
Non, j'ai juste pas dormi.
If you want, I can give you some of my mom's sleeping pills.
Tu veux les somniféres de ma mére ?
-She won't notice they're missing? -She doesn't know she takes them.
- Elie verra pas qu'il en manque ? - Elie ignore qu'elle en prends.
No, that's okay. It was something else keeping me up last night.
Non, ça ira. C‘est autre chose qui m‘a gardé éveillé cette nuit.
And again this morning.
Et encore, ce matin.
And I didn't mind.
Et ça ne m‘a pas gêné.
l was up last night. I was up this morning. I didn't mind.
Debout cette nuit, et ce matin. Et ça me gêne pas.
Those are your clues.
Tels sont vos indices.
Ooh, ooh, did the pigeon on your windowsill have more babies?
Le pigeon a encore niché sur ton rebord de fenêtre ?
-No. -Were you making another Lego movie?
- Non. - Tu refais un film Lego ?
-Because let me tell you:
- Parce que tu sais,
It's not enough to make the Legos move. They also have to capture your heart.
il suffit pas de faire bouger les Legos : il faut de l'émotion.
Okay, I'll give you one more clue.
Ok, un dernier indice.
It involved another person.
Il y a quelqu'un d‘autre d‘impliqué.
Did you get a Japanese love pillow?
Tu as un oreiller d‘amourjaponais ?
How is a Japanese love pillow another person?
En quoi est-ce quelqu'un d‘autre ?
It is if you love her and give her a name.
Si tu l'aimes et que tu lui donnes un nom.
Dr. Plimpton, I'd like you to meet my colleagues.
Dr. Plimpton, voici mes collègues.
Dr. Rajesh Koothrappali.
Le Dr. Rajesh Koothrappali.
-And not-a-doctor Howard Wolowitz. -Hi.
- Le non—docteur Howard Wolowitz. - Salut.
-l'm a big fan of your work. -Thank you.
- J‘adore votre travail. - Merci.
And, of course, you've already introduced yourself to Dr. Hofstadter.
Bien sûr, vous connaissez le Dr. Hofstadter.
-Hey, you.
- Salut, toi.
Boy, I'm kind of tuckered out.
Je suis épuisé.
How are you feeling, Elizabeth?
Et toi, Elizabeth ?
You know what? I am a little tired.
Moi aussi, je suis fatiguée.
Would you be a dear and get me a cup of coffee?
Tu veux bien aller Noir, c‘est ça ?
Actually, now I think I want it hot, brown and sweet.
J'ai soudain envie de quelque chose de café au lait.
Coming right up.
Ça vient.
What?
Quoi ?
What do you mean, "what?" It's "Halo" night.
Quoi, "quoi" ? C‘est la soirée Halo.
I can't. I'm too sick.
Je suis trop malade. Dégage.
That's why we moved "Halo" night here.
C‘est pour ça qu'on le fait ici.
I brought my mom's chicken soup.
J'ai de la soupe de poulet.
I'm not hungry.
J'ai pas faim.
ELIZABETH: Don't send him away. Let him in.
Laisse-Ie entrer.
-Who is that? -I bought a parrot.
- C‘est qui ? - Mon perroquet.
Yeah, right.
C‘est ça.
-Dr. Plimpton? -Hi.
- Dr. Plimpton ? - Salut.
-Howard, right? -Uh, yeah.
- Howard, c‘est ça ? - Oui.
Can I ask you a question, Howard?
Je peux vous poser une question ?
Do you like role-playing games?
Vous aimez les jeux de rôles ?
Yeah, sure. Heh.
Bien sûr.
In fact, I'm a dungeon master.
Je suis maitre de donjon.
Not tonight.
Pas ce soir.
Tonight, you are a deliveryman.
Ce soir, vous êtes livreur.
You've brought soup but, uh-oh, Raj and I don't have enough money to pay you.
Vous livrez une soupe, mais Raj et moi ne pouvons pas payer.
So we'll have to come to some other kind of arrangement.
On va devoir s'arranger autrement.
Beg pardon?
Je vous demande pardon ?
You figure out the details. I'm gonna change into something...
Réglez les détails. Je vais passer quelque chose
...I don't mind getting ripped off my milky flesh.
que je veux bien me faire arracher à même le corps.
What the frak?
Il se passe quoi ?
Go away.
Dégage.
She wants New Delhi, not kosher deli.
Elle veut du New Delhi, pas du kasher.
Besides, you have a girlfriend.
Et tu as une copine.
We broke up weeks ago.
On a rompu il y a des semaines.
-Why didn't you say anything? -I was waiting for the right time.
- Tu n'as rien dit. - J‘attendais le bon moment.
This is the right time.
C‘est le bon moment.
Hey, who's ready for "Halo"?
Qui veutjouer à Halo ?
Oh, this is like a nightmare. Get lost.
C‘est un cauchemar. Dégage.
The numbers are shaky enough as it is.
C‘est déjà assez compliqué comme ça.
I don't understand.
Je ne comprends pas.
Oh, good. Leonard's here.
Parfait, Leonard est la.
Good?
Parfait ?
Elizabeth? What's going on?
Elizabeth ? Que se passe-t-il ?
What's going on is you and Howard are my moving men.
Howard et toi êtes mes déménageurs.
And Raj is my new landlord.
Raj est mon nouveau proprio.
And I don't have enough money to pay any of you.
Je n'ai pas de quoi vous payer.
Is she suggesting what I think she's suggesting?
Elie suggère bien ce que je crois ?
Yup. Welcome to the Penthouse Forum.
Oui. Bienvenue sur le forum de Penthouse.
Okay, show of hands. Who's up for this?
Levez la main, qui est partant ?
We'll all be naked in front of each other.
On va se voir tout nu.
I'm out.
Je me casse.
Everybody ready?
Tout le monde est prêt ?
Follow my lead. Almost.
Suivez-moi. Ou presque.
We're going to go out into the hallway and make a dramatic entrance.
On sort et on fait une entrée spectaculaire.
Oh, good. It's so much better when everyone commits.
C‘est mieux quand tout le monde joue le jeu.
Run, run, run. Don't look back.
Fuyez, ne vous retournez pas.
I thought we had something special.
Je croyais qu'on partageait un truc.
So you say you can't pay your rent?
Alors, ce loyer ?
-Oh, Leonard? -Hey.
- Leonard ? - Salut.
I found these in the dryer.
C‘était dans Ie sèche-linge.
I'm assuming they belong to Sheldon.
C‘est à Sheldon, je présume.
Thanks. It's really hard to find these in his size.
Merci, c‘est dur d'en trouver à sa taille.
So listen.
Ecoute.
I've been meaning to talk to you about the other morning.
Je veux te parler de l‘autre matin.
PENNY: You mean you and Dr. Slutbunny?
Avec le Dr. Couchetoilà ?
Yeah, I wanted to explain.
Je veux m'expliquer.
No. You don't owe me an explanation.
Tu n'as pas le faire.
-I don't? -No, you don't.
- Non ? - Non.
So you're notjudging me?
Tu ne me juges pas ?
PENNY: Oh, I'm judging you nine ways to Sunday...
Si, je te juge comme jamais dans ma vie.
...but you don't owe me an explanation.
Mais tu n'as pas à t'expliquer.
Nevertheless, I'd like to get one on the record...
J'aimerais tout de même le faire,
...so you can understand why I did what I did.
pour que tu comprennes pourquoi je l'ai fait.
I'm listening.
J‘écoute.
She let me.
Elle a bien voulu.
[ENGLISH - US - SDH]
[FRENCH]